[Music]
w
hello and welcome back to the ask ofit
show we are into episode 214 good
evening good day to all of you I hope
you're doing great I welcome back my
regular viewers privileged to have you
on and and I would like to welcome the
new viewers as well the format of the
show is very simple you ask me questions
I answer your questions you are and in
this episode I'm going to take questions
that you have asked in the comments with
the hasht ask abijit if you want to ask
questions for future episodes you can
ask questions in the comments in the
comment or the comments of this of this
live stream or any other video on the
channel or any other community post just
use the hashtag ask abijit so I've
selected about 25 questions for today
and let's see who all is there on the
live chat with us I can see Vishnu
mohanan rashit a Imran naimi rwi
majumdar Yash Karan nwat ROV Kumar tagi
scho
mishar sorry endan Dr Atul Anita Krish
ainka Rashmi sankit ganor Batman sidhar
sing Raj purit teny Sumit Kumar Raja
Akash Kumar Amisha m hello Shashank
Kosik Sati Breeze vun Singh
Malik parbat par Muk nanal Shukla
shaa pida kotla geopolitical dub
jho Akash benergy Mani jangir Anonymous
vun Singh Malik Max rajat Duan the
silent ninja K abijit chavda mgan Ka
Bonia and lots and lots of other people
aush Pand rudra Omer hello rwi
majumdar Raja zubon eang lazy memer
crafter Leo vad wankar Kiran KK Guru
Prasad bandar bji and lots of other
people so okay let's take questions what
questions do we have uh let me find the
questions this question is by m Lovin so
apparently we are spying on Australia
what are your views on this so are we
spying on Australia what's it mean by
that so here's uh uh there's been some
Revelations apparently from the
Australian government we know that the
Americans have been claiming that India
has been trying to apparently allegedly
assassinate a khalistani terrorist who
is protected by the US right that that
panu fellow that that that whole issue
uh now the Australians are claiming that
India has been operating uh a spying
operation operation on Australian
territory so let's let's see what uh
let's find this
um okay let's do this so here's a a
report from ABC which is the Australian
Broadcasting Corporation this is from
30th April this year 2024 India's Modi
government oper operated test of spies
in Australia before being disrupted by
asio which is the Australian whatever
intelligence thing so Indian spies were
apparently klicked out of Australia
after being caught trying to steal
secrets about sensitive defense projects
and airport security as as well as
classified information on Australia's
trade relationships and so on so forth
so that's an article from 30th of
April this is from the BBC 1st of May
this year Australia sidesteps reports
that it expelled Indian spies
and the Australian government has
stocked up its closed ties with New
Delhi despite reports that two Indian
spies were expelled from the country in
2020 apparently in 2021 Australia's
intelligence Chief said that foreign
agents had been operating locally in the
previous year but he did not say their
nationality multiple news outlets
reported this week that they were far
from India and so on that's from 1st of
May this year this is from 19th of June
this is an Indian publication four
Indian spies apparently quietly expelled
by Australia for attempting to leak
sensitive
information so Australia has quietly
expelled four Indian spies for
attempting to blah blah blah blah blah
the spies purply tried to gain access to
sensitive information on Australia's
defense technology and airport security
protocols and so on and much more uh and
so on okay so that the spies developed
targeted relationships with current and
former politicians a foreign Embassy and
a State Police Service the spies
monitored their country's diaspora
Community which means Indian apparently
allegedly Indian India's diaspora and
tried to obtain classified information
about Australia's trade relationships
and so on you can you can read this and
this is from September 20 this year and
today September 22 so that's just a
couple of days ago so Indian spies
allegation Australian PM Albanese says
such matters rais
privately what I do is act
diplomatically and have those
discussions and that will no doubt be
something that is raised says Australian
prime minister Anthony
albanes uh and yeah so that's the deal
okay that's the uh claim that is being
made that's the allegation that's being
made that India uh was operating a nest
of spies in Australia and the spies were
allegedly according to these claims
monitoring the Indian diaspora they were
C ating relationships with with current
Australian politicians former Australian
politicians at least one foreign Embassy
uh they were trying to and so on okay
whatever you saw the claims you can read
up at your leisure if you like that's
the claim that's been made now as always
there is no evidence that is uh
presented to substantiate the claim it's
just a claim that's made and uh so so
what do I make of this look in so what
do I make of what I make of this this is
very simple Every Nation spies on the
others okay let's be very clear about
this when you have a foreign Embassy on
your territory you have to treat it as a
nest of spies Israel is very clear very
explicit about this if any member of the
Israeli Defense Forces IDF is discovered
to have let's say uh accepted a
ride in vehicle that has foreign
diplomatic plates that person is court
marshall immediately because all foreign
diplomats are considered to be foreign
spies by Israel and that's how you to
look at all diplomatic activity in some
way or the other it is a form of spying
you could you could consider it to be a
form of spying except maybe the highest
level so your High Commissioner will
probably not be a spy there'll be a
diplomat uh the Ambassador won't be a
spy that person will be a Diplomat
usually uh but you have military
attaches and trade atach and whatnot
okay all kinds of attaches you have who
have different uh uh functions to carry
out and some of these functions involve
Gathering intelligence overly covertly
whatever so there's generally a certain
percentage of trained career spies
professional spies in any embassy it's
it's well known everyone knows
this so when it comes to a nation like
like India
historically historically uh an also ran
kind of country historically a nation
with no no ambition which was once
actually stated explicitly by prime
minister manm Singh that India has no
aspirations or Ambitions of being a
great power we just want to exist
quietly in peace and please leave us
alone that sort of thing and we
will that's that's the kind of statement
Mr Manon Singh made Dr Manon Singh made
so historically India has been like this
the past since 47 right and now India is
a different kind of nation India is
India's economy is growing rapidly
India's overall hard power is expanding
India's
interests are expanding we have
interests in in a variety of
geographical zones uh for a variety of
reasons
uh it's something to do with Supply
chains for example it's uh something to
do with access to resources in various
parts of the world and so much more so
much more so naturally as your
interests expand you would need you
would want and need to gather
information that is pertinent and
relevant to that
and it's possible that there may be a
little bit of maybe some some grain of
Truth to what the uh what these
allegations claim maybe possibly perhaps
okay I have no idea it's possible there
could be some gra grain of truth is is
it also not true that all the other
foreign embassies in India spy on India
of course they do it's very clear it's
known uh India expelled a bunch of
Canadians last year didn't didn't we a
bunch of Canadian spies from the
Canadian embassy or consulate or
whatever it was from probably from Del
if I'm not mistaken I may be wrong but
you can look it up so it's it's a
routine
thing so it's no big
news that an embassy would spy upon its
host country
no big deal but to announce this and
make you know publish this and and tell
the media about this that is kind of
unusual usually these cloaken dagger
things are done behind behind the scenes
away from public View and there's a
whole lot of intrigue that goes on
behind this so to make this public
is well the the purpose of that would be
to apply some kind of pressure on
India and Australia as we know is a
nation that is essentially owned and
controlled by the US I mean Australia is
a wonderful nation very nice people we
in India have great cricketing ties with
Australia and there's a significant
Indian diaspora there but overall if you
look at how the relationships work
Australia is part of the five eyes
Coalition or whatever you want to call
it five eyes partnership uh Australia is
one of the anglosphere Nations one of
the closest allies of the US um and you
could say I mean there's a permanent US
military presence in
Australia the Australian government has
also in the past allowed America the
United States to test nuclear weapons on
Australian soil so the relationship is
extremely close and you could to some
extent say that the US is Australia's
guaran of security and what and much
more and the relationship is kind of
kind of comparable to the relationship
the US has with
Japan so so if the Australians have made
such claims allegations you could
perhaps imagine that there could be an
American angle in this the Americans uh
before this the Canadians have made
various claims right Justin Trudeau made
various claims about uh whatever the
entire Fiasco that happened last year
and the relationship the The Diplomatic
relationship between the two Nations
reached all time laws because of Justin
tudo uh and the allegations he and his
and his uh
government made about India one could
also imagine that there could be a us
hand behind this the US controls the
five eyes Coalition the anglosphere the
US is the most powerful Nation all these
other nations are its various client
states the closest clients and they'll
do what they're told so if the US wants
to apply pressure on India
diplomatically it can have it done via
all its client states the UK the the the
the the UK Australia Canada and New
Zealand and various other EU EU Nations
NATO Nations what not it's got a whole
array of choices at its disposal so My
Views are that the US is trying to apply
pressure on India from a variety of
fronts the Canadian allegations the
American allegations about India
allegedly trying to assassinate or or or
neutralize a terrorist who is shielded
and and harbored by the Americans these
Australian allegations it's all about
creating this this sense of Siege we are
being besieged on from all sides that
sort of thing so what does it mean it
means that they want India to change its
approach to certain things what could
those things be one is obviously the
relationship with Russia the Americans
want India to cut off its relationship
with Russia and become a complete us
client State a vasal state India is too
big too large to become a US vasal state
but the Americans want to do want this
to
happen and um things like that so this
is all part of us pressure tactics on
India that's my view on this whether
it's true or not it's beside the point
every nation spies on each on the other
the Americans have a fulltime I assure
you flying spying operation on India and
that's no big deal as as a great power
as a superow they would be spying on
everybody and it makes sense for them to
do do that so if India is also doing a
little bit of spying somewhere or the
other what's the big deal I mean it's no
surprise to anyone but yeah so that's my
view on this m
matter okay
nav R 7931 says considering the recent
event in Lebanon operated by mosad where
widespread explosions of electronic
devices have occurred since yesterday
which is the September 17th 18th and
which may escalate in the coming days I
have two concerns one or questions one
does the Indian foreign intelligence
agency raw RN
aw uh lack the necessary expertise to
neutralize our Targets in a similar
manner secondly how vulnerable are we as
in India to such an attack given our
heavy Reliance on electronic products
and components manufactured by China and
other foreign suppliers excellent
questions very relevant to the situation
very relevant to India from India's
perspective so first of all I have
spoken about this yesterday and
yesterday's live stream during the live
chat live stream and uh let me reiterate
that I as far as I know the there has
been no uh
admission by mad that it is behind
what's happened so they have not claimed
credit they have not uh admitted that
they are behind this but for but I think
it's very clear that most likely uh mad
is behind this they may not be alone in
being behind this but they certainly are
behind this and if you look at the uh
uh responses on social media responses
and and and statements Etc on social
media from various Israeli accounts
including accounts that are official
accounts government accounts and so on
it's kind of indirectly taking I mean I
mean celebrating and and taking credit
for what's happened indirectly without
explicitly saying
so so I believe that it's definitely
mosad is a major player in what happened
but I don't think mosad is alone in this
I don't think they would have been able
to do this without the cooperation and
and uh participation of us intelligence
because we're talking about almost a
global level supply chain infiltration
and exploitation so I think it's it's
could be a joint operation between mosad
and the Americans that tells you how
close the relationship between Israel
and the US is also so this is entirely
my view it's you can consider it to be
speculation you can consider it to be an
educated intelligent guest if you think
I'm intelligent but that's what I what I
believe I don't think mad would be alone
in this now what does this um what are
the repercussions of this what does this
mean going forward for the rest of the
world well first of all it it tells you
that mosad and the US can essentially
infiltrate and and
uh compromise any supply chain
Well the West which is the US
essentially owns the entire world Supply
chains which is why it's a superpower
and it owns and and controls them with
the help of its incredible power
projection ability it can it can
intervene militarily anywhere on the
globe 60 minutes notice 30 minutes
whatever you want to call it two hours
notice 1 hour notice which is why all
the supply chains are under their
control uh they also control the EU they
control the NATO Nations they control
Nations like Taiwan South Korea and so
much of the
high-tech uh Supply chains are
controlled by the US and it's it's not
that difficult for them
to um you know compromise some element
in the supply
chain so um that tells the world that if
you use electronic products that contain
lithium ion batteries you could be next
you could be if you fall a foul of of
somebody in the West the us or Israel
you could be next uh I've seen lots of
world leaders carrying you know using
iPhones I I hear that iPhones exploded
in in Lebanon lots of iPhones exploded
that's what one hears that is a big big
big uh you know message to the whole
world from the US not just from Israel
from the US that listen no one's safe
everyone knows that iPhones and and
Android phones and and the Chinese
phones Etc are Perpetual listening
devices they're Gathering harvesting all
of your data your movements data about
your movements data about whatever you
do and it's also a listening device it's
always on it's always next to you so
it's not just that now it's something
that could kill you if if
uh the those Powers so
desire so it's going to uh
definitely you know turn on some some
Panic Bells at various levels in World
governments and uh I would say from
India's perspective we are tremendously
vulnerable to such a potential the to
the potential to potentially being the
target of such an attack whether it's
from the west or from China because most
Indians I believe use uh I don't know I
think Chinese phones a lot in India
which and I'm not sure if the Chinese
have the ability to make lithiumion
batteries explode or to slip something a
few grams of some explosive into a
battery without anyone realizing
something's being tampered with I'm not
sure if the Chinese have the ability to
do that maybe they
do so it makes India vulnerable not just
to the Chinese also to the West right
because Indians use a variety of phones
some of these are made in China some of
these are Android phones made somewhere
else and some could be iPhones iPhones
could be a minority Market but market
share but there you have it
so I think India is extremely vulnerable
to this uh until India starts
manufacturing everything inous atat
which we keep on the slogan sounds very
nice but what are we doing about it I'm
sure we're doing something or the other
but we need more so India is extremely
vulnerable to the potential of to being
the potential Target of such an attack
whether it's from China whether it's
from West
wherever uh that's why second does Ro
lack the necessary expertise to
neutralize our Targets in a similar
manner I'm not sure I have no
idea um when it comes to intelligence uh
capabilities you keep it quiet if you
have the ability to do that you don't
advertise it you keep
quiet uh hide your capabilities right uh
that's what ding shopping said and and
buy your time well forgot about buy your
time but you certainly should hide your
capabilities uh now the question is
what would it hypothetically take for a
nation X to carry out such an attack on
a nation y okay I'll not take names
let's say Nation X is India for example
okay so what does it take what would it
take for a nation like India to to carry
out a similar attack on some
hypothetical Nation why you would have
to know exactly where that Nation Y is
sourcing whatever lithium ion batteries
for whatever for whether it's for cell
phones whether it is for laptops whether
it is for something else electric cars
whatever it is maybe Nationwide doesn't
use electric cars maybe it's too
backward but whatever I'm just say we'll
need to know exactly where it's sourcing
these things from lithon batteries
whatever other Toaster air condition
whatever it is you want to Target pagers
in case then you have to be needed you
need the ability to infiltrate that
supply chain and tamper with the battery
or whatever component you want to tamper
with and thirdly you need the ability to
remotely
detonate that on demand these three
capabilities need to be in place does Ro
have that well I think only row knows
whether it can do it or not we have
never carried out such an such an
operation there have been these reports
of uh unknown gunmen carrying out
whatever attacks in Pakistan well maybe
it's Ro maybe it's not we have no idea
of saying that but that's not that's not
Hightech that's that's that's uh you
if if that's indeed done by roow then
they using human assets to carry out the
targeted uh eliminations of
terrorists but it's not being done in
this high-tech manner so in case the
ability is there it's being hidden or
maybe the ability isn't there so I am
not the right person to ask because I am
in no manner shape or form associated
with Indian intelligence obviously right
so that's what I can say so those three
capabilities need to be in place for any
intelligence agency to carry out a
similar kind of attack so it's it's you
need to be able to to infiltrate so
first of all know where the materials
are being sourced from secondly you need
the ability to infiltrate and compromise
those Supply chains without anyone
knowing thirdly you need the Hightech
capability to blow up those devices on
demand remotely and that to
simultaneously so you need a tremendous
amount of technical Etc capabilities to
be able to do that that's what I would
say
okay Damian Rivera says in the context
of exploding devices can superpower
defense exporters remotely turn off
weapons like missiles and fighter jets
that they sell to us that's a great
question I think I've kind of touched on
this in the past but let's once again
revisit this topic uh let's say the US
Super Power Defense exporters like loid
Martin whatever else right
uh we're talking about American missiles
American weapon systems and they sell
General atomics those Reaper drones and
and sea Guardian drones and all kinds of
stuff right uh so let's say the
Americans have sold a certain weapons
system to a friendly Nation let's say to
Australia in the 1980s they sold F-15
fighter planes to the Australians the
Americans and Australia is essentially
well one of the closest allies the US
has right
five
eyes so the Americans sold a bunch of
F-15 fighter planes to the
Australians and the Australians very
rapidly discovered that when they take
these fighter planes for a for a spin
and as a simulation they try to lock the
targeting mechanism of the fighter plane
onto let's say some some ship in the sea
it would refuse to lock on to that ship
it would allow the pilots to to lock the
targeting mechanism only on
predetermined targets that the Americans
have programmed into the f-15s and
nothing else the Australians could not
do a thing about
it I mean as the owner of the weapon
system the F-15 fighter plane that you
have paid for you've bought it you
should be able to use it to Target
whatever you want right but they could
not and then apparently they hacked into
the American database or whatever and
eventually they were able to to after
like 20 20 plus years they were able to
modify the software and and make the
f-15s do whatever they wanted so the
Americans have done that so that's not
exactly remotely turning off weapons but
that's about uh you
know making weapons uh giving giving you
weapons that W serve the purpose that
won't do what you want them to do
handicapped
um
but I'm sure it's also possible for the
Americans to remotely switch off turnoff
weapons that uh they may not want you to
use for example pakistanis the
pakistanis have a bunch of
f-16s and a few years ago there was the
whole balakot thing right uh India took
out a
terrorist uh nest of snakes somewhere in
K pakun and then the Pakistani is next
day ret by by sending a bunch of f-16s
across the border to to Target some
Indian infrastructure if the Americans
wanted they could have prevented those
f-16s from taking
off so I'm sure the Americans have the
ability to do that and the same goes for
missiles and whatnot I think the
Americans can do whatever they want with
missile systems and and weapon systems
they have designed and
built so if you for example if India has
chinuk helicopters or India has those
Reaper drones or whatever and
hypothetically in a completely
hypothetical scenario if India were to
you try and use those those uh drones to
let's say do surveillance activities on
American warships maybe you won't get
any data out out of it or something like
that so they can control everything
you're doing so that's the the Peril
that you are under when you purchase
Weapons
Systems from the superpower now will
that also apply to weapons you buy from
Russia
France I think when it comes to Russian
weapons they have been tried and tested
in Battlefield conditions and the
Russians have never uh prevented
remotely or whatever India from using
weapon systems but the possibility is
always there so that's why you have to
be completely self-reliant when it comes
to weapon systems every single thing has
to be manufactured at home whether it is
a bullet whether it is a shell casing
whether it's howt are whether it's
artillery pieces whether it's tanks
whether it
is missile boats Corvettes warships uh
destroyers aircraft carriers fighter
planes helicopters missiles short range
missiles drones whatever it is you have
to submarines and the list goes on you
have to manufacture it yourself that's
the only way you can be 100% sure that
it's going to work as per your
expectations so yes it's a great
question you've asked and
the answer is they can turn it off if
they
want okay a couple of questions and I'm
sure there are many more about this a
snaky gaming 1438 says Russia says says
that it supports Pakistan joining bricks
what are My Views about this and
Anonymous t6n says what do you think of
the Russian Deputy Prime Minister's
visit to Pakistan what was the reason
for this visit and is Russia warming up
to Pakistan once again okay okay now we
know let's understand the context the
broader context of this entire matter we
know that in 2022 there was a coup in
Pakistan and Imran Khan was ousted the
Apparently democratically elected prime
minister was oued and some other fellow
was put in place Sharif right the the
Shabah Sharif I think I I think he is
still the prime minister of Pakistan so
the Imran Khan experiment ended he's now
in jail where he languishes
and Shabah Sharif or whoever is the it
is is the prime minister doesn't matter
who the prime minister is the Army is
actually the entity that controls
Pakistan so the the out of Imran
Khan was a turning point in the sense
that it until Imran Khan was prime
minister he was trying to bring the
nation closer into China's Embrace and
after Imran Khan's out the nation once
again
Pakistan once again went into the
American Embrace and after that you had
the visits multiple visits of of
Pakistani defense uh individuals you
know top ranking def military uh leaders
to the US meeting with the US defense
establishment and all that so Pakistan
is very much back in the US EMB it's
it's once again a US basal State okay so
that's what Pakistan is it is once again
a US vasal state now when when you are a
US Ally and you want to join
bricks doesn't make sense right doesn't
add up bricks the Americans see it as an
anti-west kind of
Coalition right it's it's part of the
uh of the attempt by Nations like Russia
China Etc to bifurcate the world order
and it's it's an alternative to the
Western so-called rules BAS world order
right the bricks thing so if a nation
like Pakistan which is a US Ally us
wasad wants to join bricks it raises
question marks doesn't it so when Russia
says when Russia says you know says blah
its words when Russia says it supports
Pakistan joining bricks it's words it is
words it's not an action I can say
anything I want politicians make a
million statements a year
and most of the statements essentially
unfortunately are meaningless so you can
say one thing do another that's that's
that's the oldest trick in the book in
politics geopolitics whatever so when
Russia says that it supports Pakistan
joining bricks it's it means nothing
more or less it
is to keep the the game going
essentially it's a PL to keep the game
going what does it take for a nation to
join bricks that's that's the question
we to ask ourselves right what does it
take for a nation to be able to join
obviously there are clear rules when it
comes to a nation how a new n Nation can
become a new member of bricks there are
very clear rules about this and and I
think that under bricks rules the the
leaders of the
founding members founding nations of
bricks they have to decide on the mer or
demerits of each new membership
application with full consultation and
the decision is made by
consensus that's I believe how uh the
uh new membership applications are are
are
processed so if India were to object to
Pakistan's application to become a
member of bricks it's very hard to see
how that rule can be
circumvented so essentially it is the BR
I Nations their leaders who will decide
by consensus and I'm I'm sure it has to
be unanimous consensus that a new nation
should be admitted into breaks so if
Brazil
agrees China
agrees India
disagrees Russia abstains and South
Africa agrees then there's one
abstention and one disagreement or let's
say everyone agrees but India disagrees
then once again there's a disagreement
and there is no consensus
so without consensus it's not going to
be possible for a new application to be
approved uh without the whole structure
of the whole system breaking down so I
think Russia understands this very well
I think Russia's relationship with India
is way more important than it Russia
relationship with Pakistan which is a
fair weather Ally to just about
everybody which is a US
asset
um so I think so that's what I make of
it I think it's just words now uh what
do I make of the Russian Deputy Prime
Minister's visit to Pakistan what's the
reason for this is Russia warming up to
Pakistan once again or I think Russia
just wants to keep uh relationships
going so they've sent a low ranking
person not even the Prime Minister the
Deputy Prime Minister on a visit to
Pakistan to discuss this old bricks
thing probably at the beest of China the
Chinese probably are playing multiple
games they always play 78 dimensional
chess don't they the Chinese they think
that they are extremely inscrutable and
uh opaque and all that so they most
likely the Chinese would have asked
Russia to send a reasonably high ranking
person to Pakistan to continue uh the
relationship and the Chinese probably
want Pakistan to to become a member of
bricks and the the Chinese obviously
will know that without consensus which
means India's approval Pakistan can't
become a member of bricks it's just a
game to keep the pressure up the Chinese
are are currently engaged in a possible
disengagement M on the India Tibet
border and possibly some kind of better
relationship with India but they will
play all kinds of games the same time in
parallel so I think a lot there's a
significant China Shadow over all this
so I don't think the Russians would like
to have bricks in I mean Pakistan in
bricks I don't think the Russians will
want to antagonize
India the Russians have very few friends
and we have a very old relationship and
relationship which has a significant
amount of trust you cannot just you know
destroy such a relationship by making a
few rash moves so I don't think it's
it's a big deal I think it's unlikely
that Pakistan will become a member of
bricks even the Turks have applied to be
a member of bricks turkey wants to be a
member of bricks turkey is an official
member of NATO I mean how on Earth can
you be on both sides so there's all
kinds of games being played right now
okay Salah hotro Salah utro says
Pakistani hockey players supporting
China in Stand after getting humiliated
by China in the semi-finals that do seem
controversial because Pakistan is
stronger than China as a hockey playing
nation is this because of the heavy
loans China has given to Pakistan please
save Pakistan look sir I am who am I to
save Pakistan I I have no ill will
towards the citizens of Pakistan those
people of Pakistan we were once the same
people we still have shared blood don't
we uh so I have nothing against the
common people of Pakistan uh I don't
wish them anything bad but Pakistan
obviously you know the deal right
Pakistan is a problem for India big big
problem historically and and continuing
now the deal is this um we have the we
recently had the recently concluded uh
um Asian champ Champion TR
hockey hockey is one of my favorite
sports very interesting sport very
fastpaced
Sport and uh India won the the trophy I
be defeating China I believe in the
final one- zero we should have had like
five six goals but we did scored one now
the deal is uh
Pakistan were were defeated by China in
the semi-finals not sure I didn't watch
the match I'm not sure what the score
line is but Pakistan were beaten by
China and then in the fin China plays
India and the Pakistani hockey players
were in The Stance supporting
China and the point Salah is Raising
here is that even the Pakistani defeat
to China is controversial because
Pakistan is a way stronger team compared
to
China well we know that in Asia India is
probably the strongest team and the fact
that India was able to defeat China only
one Z would indicate that China have
become probably a better team than they
were in the past so perhaps the
Pakistani defeat to China may not be
that controversial but it's kind of
humiliating for the Chinese for the
Pakistani players to uh appear in the
stance for the final and and and uh
support the team that defeated them just
because China is playing India I mean
that's kind of you're amazing yourself
you you're you're degrading and
humiliating yourself uh is it because of
heavy heavy loans or whatever I think
the Chinese have given loans to Pakistan
and all but Pakistan is now on the US uh
side of things I don't think it's
because the Chinese have given heavy
loans I think it's because of some sort
of hatred for
India I think that's that's the case I
don't think it's because the Chinese
have given loans to to Pakistan and
they've instructed the CH the Pakistani
players that U appear in the stands and
support China I don't think that's the
case I think there seems to be a
significant level among the ordinary
Pakistani population of of hatred
towards India and that's something that
the entire system has has Brainwashed
the people into believing right India is
our enemy India is evil there's some
religious angle into it in there also
the education system also contributes a
great deal to to all this I think it's
multiple levels of things but I think
there is
genuine uh hatred towards India in
Pakistan uh and that's unfortunate
really unfortunate see see how that's
that's how how social engineering works
that's how brainwashing works we in
India we don't pose any threat to
Pakistan we don't look every war that's
that's happened the pakistanis have
started right we didn't start any of the
wars we finish the wars we that's a
different
story excuse
me so I think that's the case I think
that there is genuine dislike hatred of
India and that's why they will support
whoever is playing against India India
uh when it comes to saving Pakistan look
I think it's up to the people of
Pakistan if you want to save Pakistan
the people of Pakistan have to do
something perhaps take matters into
their own hands uh the thing that you
have to save Pakistan from you have to
first identify that and that entity is
the Pakistani military the Pakistani
military is a parasitic organism that is
slowly that has been slowly strangling
Pakistan and leeching the lifeblood out
of
Pakistan in exploiting the people of
Pakistan and there's no development in
the nation Pakistan was so different in
the 1980s it was almost like a booming
economy and now see what they've done to
it uh so the entity you have to save
your nation from is the Pakistani
military and all the other organizations
and whatever that is associated with the
military uh that's what you would to
save Pakistan
prom and that's unfortunately not up to
us here in India it's the people of
Pakistan who have to do it themselves
and yeah so I would say I wish the best
to the people of Pakistan I have no ill
will towards the people the ordinary
person people of Pakistan but Pakistan
as a nation I unfortunately regrettably
see it as an artificial temporary Nation
artificial 100% it is and temporary well
I think time will tell us that Pakistan
is a temporary experiment eventually it
will it will disintegrate when the the
the support of the foreign powers is
taken away whenever that happens then
it's a matter of
time okay Joy deat 5088 says in
Bangladesh it seems that a large part of
chagang will be uprooted ringas on one
side Chittagong Hill trct on the other V
minority Hindus are also scared India
should do something for us otherwise we
can't live in Bangladesh okay let's talk
about gong once
again uh where do we have the map okay
we haven't opened the map today so let's
open the map where is
map so this is the map and we go to
Bangladesh East Pakistan whatever you
want to call it and we are once again
talking about CH Chong like we were
doing yesterday and this used to be a
Hindu Buddhist majority area similar to
silad similar to Raj Shahi rangpur I
don't know why we gave those territories
away our wonderful founding fathers or
so-called leaders of independence of the
independence movement they gave up our
territories as a gift because it belong
to them right so they give up these
territories now um there's there's been
oppression happening in chhat in the
chagang hill tracks region for a very
long time the chakmas have been
persecuted like anything by the
bangladeshis for decades before that by
the East
pakistanis uh on the to the south of the
chagang region you have the Rakin state
uh Rakin state where is Rakin State
wherever it is and that's where the
ringas are found and the
ringas lots of them have been settled in
the Cox Bazar Etc area so lots of ringas
are to be found in chagang those who are
not diverted into India and sent across
various sent to various parts of India
those are sheltered in various parts of
this region CH Chong
region so if ringas over here and you
all that and U and as we know ever since
the coup happened there's been this this
concerted uh persecution of Hindus
that's happening attacks on Hindus Hindu
temples are being destroyed Hindu people
have been you know attacked killed what
not there kind of a prgram happening
against Hindus right now so very very
scary situation for Hindus which is
unfolding as we speak right now the
media will not report it
obviously including the Indian media
they won't report this but it's
happening and you see reports of this on
social media when whenever people get
the the opportunity they're uploading
videos of what's being done to them so
it's it's a really bad situation for the
Hindus of Bangladesh and Joy deat says
India should do something for us
otherwise we cannot live in
Bangladesh what can India do is the
question right what should India do what
can India do can India do something
India is very capable of doing something
very much
so
um what can one thing India can do is
offer Refuge to the Hindus of Bangladesh
so open the borders and if you're a
Hindu you're allowed in now lots of the
Indian media and various political
parties will
will will complain and and create a
Ruckus about this that you are
discriminating on the basis of religion
that sort of thing right but let's say
India makes this happen then very soon
there will be no Hindus left in
Bangladesh and one more territory that
we give up so rather than doing that I
would that India should uh support the
Hindus of Bangladesh in self-defense
give them funding give them arms give
them ammunition give them whatever they
need to to make a stand and not give up
their lands ancestral lands and perhaps
if if the government of India has the
fortitude we could you know have we
could uh induce the creation of of a a
nation of a Hindu Nation out of bang
ladesh out of the areas of rangapur Raj
Shah perhaps silat could be part of it
perhaps CH the Chong Hill track region
could be could be part of it you know
something could be done but the question
is does the government of India have the
fortitude to do that or is it just talk
talk talk talk
talk historically even the past 10 years
it's it's all been talk remember that
one statement about baluchistan it was
just a statement nothing was ever done
so um either India should just offer
Refuge to all the Bangladeshi Hindus
which means that Bangladesh will be
empty of Hindus very soon or it should
give the Hindus of Bangladesh full
support like we say full supports are
right full support in in terms of uh
funds arms ammunition whatever they need
to make a stand and perhaps cve out a
separate nation out of Bangladesh
because Bangladesh is Pakistan is also
an artificial Nation right historically
it's been our territory Indian Territory
uh so that's what I would say needs to
happen India should
certainly help the Hindus but not in the
sense of giving them shelter maybe in
the sense of supporting their just fight
for for freedom in their own land I
think that's what we need to do but the
question is very big the very big
question is can is India is the
government of India willing of willing
to do do this it's certainly capable of
doing this is it willing to do this
depending on the various geopolitical
calculations and all that well if you
look at things I think nothing will
happen unfortunately I mean we changed
something on paper we removed article
370 from Jammu and Kashmir right 2019
it's been five years how many kashmiri
Hindus have been allowed to return to
Jammu and Kashmir nothing right nobody
so we only do things on paper and then
we we say that we are very
strong but we don't change facts on the
ground that's what a strong Nation does
we areen even doing it within our own
borders so do you think we'll do it in
Bangladesh I don't think this government
is strong enough to do that
unfortunately it's all talk very
disappointing but that's the reality I
see
unfortunately okay ad Guru Prasad says
in recent qu meeting USA said it will
support India for permanent as as a for
India's quest for a permanent seat on
the US un Security Council UNC permanent
membership does the US really mean it
and even if the US does mean it how do
we deal with
China's
veto when it comes to voting for a
permanent
seat look recent a couple of questions
ago we discussed U Russia
support for Pakistan's entry into bricks
right and I told you it's it's just
words words are cheap you can say
anything you want you don't have to act
on it similarly the Americans have been
saying for a long time they'll support
this they'll support that they're going
to support
nothing they will never share a single
percentage point of the power that they
have okay so it's just words it's never
going to
happen and let's say they even mean it
like Guru Prasad says
how do we deal with China's vote for the
permanent SE the Chinese will not agree
Chinese will exercise their veto what
can India do about this absolutely
nothing my point is let's stop obsessing
with the United United Nations security
Council permanent membership we had the
chance of getting that in the 1950s and
so on but our magnificent prime minister
Shri Neu G decided to uh prioritize
China over
India well known and as such we lost our
opportunity and
uh now there's nothing we can do about
it so we need to stop obsessing over
this permanent seat it's kind of a
status symbol we want we should obsess
over our economic growth over the real
power that we can ACR for ourselves with
our own two hands that's what we need to
obsess
over okay forget about the UN Security
Council permanent SE all of that stuff
just work on your economy work as hard
as possible year after year after year
do it for 20 years 30 years and then
what who cares about the UN permanent un
Security Council permanent seat you'll
become so big it won't be relevant it
won't even matter so that's what we need
to do forget about chasing status Chase
real power Chase real
strength you know it's like
uh you want a bodybuilding title without
putting in the hard work two three years
of lifting the weights over and over
again year day after day after day the
grind I want the title I want the crown
but I will not put in the hard work of
lifting those thousand tens of thousands
of kilos cumulative of we of
weight so forget about the title ignore
the crown go to gym every single day and
lift the godamn weights do it over and
over and over again take care of your
health take care of your diet nutrition
all of that and see what happens in a
few years you'll be so big nobody will
ask you whether you won this title or
not no one will care what title you won
or did not win you your the simple fact
of your
existence and the immensity of your
being will be enough to tell everybody
who the real king is that's what you
need to do let's stop chasing status
Chase real
power okay what other questions uh do we
have
okay a couple of questions about Manipur
Manipur is always on the on the agenda
these days for for good reason Shan says
900 cookie militants have entered
Manipur is Cookie Land way to close are
are we so close to losing the Northeast
and Anand says recent reports say that
cookie terrorists entered from Myanmar
into Manipur what are my thoughts about
this what are my thoughts about this
this has been happening for
years and this report that one hears
from wherever one hears this uh the
report is that 9900 cookie terrorists
have entered Manipur the question is in
what time frame the last 24 hours last 7
days last one month last8 85 years what
time frame are you talking
about we know that cookie terrorists
have been entering Manipur since the the
events of May 3 last year when the whole
thing blew up and the cookies Unleashed
Mayhem against the natives of Manipur we
have seen so many video reports of you
know Drone footage and all of of cookie
terrorists in in long lines entering
Manipur from from Myanmar and other
places other places too H wearing
uniforms and carrying all kinds of
weapons it's known they have you could
see hundreds of them at that time itself
early last year not early last year I
mean June July August around that
time they have been entering into
entering Manipur for a long time what
are my thoughts about this my thoughts
are that the border is open the previous
governments have ensured that we have
this open border policy with with
Myanmar and the previous governments of
India Central governments they ensured
that they themselves brought in cookie
cookie uh immigrants into India and
settled them in Manipur and then gave
them paperwork and all that and many of
them are in very high positions in the
Indian bureaucracy and whatnot even at
the central level today that's what
previous Indian governments did they
created the problem Modi is not dealing
with the problem somehow he has to he
has no
choice so what do I make of this it's a
disaster situation it's a disaster but
Modi has no choice but to solve the
problem I look why does Modi look weak
these days Manipur is a big reason for
that Manipur is a big reason for that
more than one year we are facing the
brunt of foreign terrorism they're
dropping bombs from drones on a capital
city of an Indian State and we are doing
nothing about it and there's so much
more now we are taking steps to rectify
the situation taking out the Assam
rifles from Manipur and bringing in crpf
and all that so I mean the
mismanagement of Manipur past several
decades 1950s 60s onwards it has taken
its toll
cumulatively all of that we have to be
undone and so much has gone wrong so
much wrong has been done in Manipur and
across the Far East other states also
but Manipur is the people of Manipur
have suffered the worst because they're
Hindus right Hindus have to suffer
because they didn't convert now they're
converting now lots of indigenous
manipuri Hindus are converting to
Christianity good job good job good job
let's do it right what was her name Sita
Dei the the lady boxer got baptized to
some some some Christian
faith so that's that's what's happening
uh is
kiland way too close are we are we close
to having Cil land I think we we still U
kiland look cookie land is is an
artificial imaginary nation that the U
the foreign powers want to create cookie
land for Christ out of uh parts of Burma
Parts very parts of Manipur mizoram and
parts of Bangladesh so are we there is
Cookland happening now not quite not
quite I don't think India will give up
Manipur and mizoram that easily but uh
the terror will continue the terrorist
activities will continue I don't think
we're going to lose Manipur and and
mizoram but we may lose the hearts and
minds of the people because they've been
suffering they've been shot
at they've been bombed and the
government has done not a thing about it
the Prime Minister doesn't speak about
it he doesn't visit
Manipur the one time he speaks about
Manipur is to say something else so it's
dispiriting if you are a person who
lives there right abject weakness from
the government of India is being
displayed and that is why Prime Minister
Modi looks so weak right now and he's
kind of
lost lost that um Aura of inven ability
he had Manipur has a lot to do with this
and let me say this again I've said this
before that I think his political career
will depend on what he does in
Manipur
okay um tirupati Balaji girar and hybrid
devil what's my opinion on the Shri
tirupati Balaji ladu issue and what are
my thoughts on the trupa dastan Andhra
Pradesh controversy over using animal
fat in Prasad
so I have not looked into this in in in
great detail as to what happened which
organization was behind this and so on
what I know is that it has been
discovered that the tirupati Balaji
Temple Prasad lus were contaminated with
with animal fat beef and pork
fat now this is
unacceptable my first question is has
the Prime Minister made any statements
about
this has the prime minister of India
spoken about this this is not a small
matter the Prime Minister likes to make
statements about all kinds of things in
manat and whatnot has the prime minister
of India spoken about
this it's a very big matter this is
unacceptable I have said this in the
past that India is the world's most
hinduphobic country do you
see me being proven right once again
unfortunately
is the media making a big deal of this
no imagine this happened
to some other religion H there are two
other foreign religions on Indian soil
imagine something like this is done to
one of those two religions the entire
Global media will rise up in chorus and
the Indian media will support them but
right now when this has happened this
unacceptable sacrilege has happened no
one's talking about this no it's no big
deal prime minister is
quiet most of the people are quiet most
of the people don't care most Indians
now look upon their own ancestral belief
system Hinduism whatever we call it as
some kind of exotic thing from the
past and it doesn't really matter oh
there is contamination in everything
what's the big deal right so going by
this it looks like Hinduism will cease
to exist by the end of the century Maybe
by 2050 Maybe by 2100 because you people
us all I would say I would not say you
people we all have kind of lost touch
with who we are invisibly don't care
anymore no outrage no nothing if this
was done to another religion the entire
world would be up in arms when something
like this happened
in
1857 we rose up against the foreign
oppressor and we launched a war of
independence Nationwide subcontinent
wise War subcontinent wide war of
independence today not a whisper not a
not a squeak everyone's quiet I'm not
saying everybody is quiet many people
are extremely upset about this but the
media is quiet the government is quiet
the Prime Minister hasn't said a word as
far as I know no big deal let the matter
die out we'll have some inquiry and at
the end of the day nothing will
happen this the government governance
Machinery the media Machinery all of
this is arrayed up against you against
our civilization we are still a
colonized Nation do you see that we are
still a colonized civilization and they
are in the process of dismantling our
civilization piece by piece and they'
have brainwashed our children and
multiple generations to such an extent
that we don't care we are empathetic we
will watch our
OT whatever what entertainment and we
happy we'll watch our Bollywood movies
and dance to Bollywood music and that's
what gives us happiness to hell with is
what what is religion who cares oh there
was some contamination there's
contamination in everything extremely
unfortunate I would say that we need to
rise up I'm not saying in arms but we
cannot let this matter die
out um whoever is behind this needs to
be uh brought to
task in
the in the most appropriate manner
according to the laws
that's what needs to happen we simply
cannot let this matter die
out yala says did the end of Hindu
monarchy of Nepal involve the Betrayal
of the military as M Maat said and you
see political power flows from the
barrel of a gun or did the end of the
Hindu monarchy of Nepal simply involve
the Cowardly voluntary abdication of the
nepales king here's what happened in the
mid 1990s a maist rebellion erupted
maist
terrorists fighting the government with
arms ammunition weapons from the jungles
from the
hills later much later it emerged that
India was supporting them who I will
simply ask you a simple question in the
90s when this entire thing happened who
was the who was the Indian Prime
Minister what government did we have
okay that's homework for you look it
up so at that time the Indian government
supported the maist terrorists who are
fighting the Hindu monarchy of Nepal and
this terrorist uh
movement went on from the mid 1990s all
the way to the mid 2000s 2005
2006 in 200 2001 whenever it happened I
don't remember which year look it up the
entire royal family of Nepal was
massacred and the laid the blame on on
on the Crown Prince
dendra and and queen ashwaria king
birendra they were assassinated the
whole family was assassinated and
apparently then the Crown Prince turned
the gun on himself very very convenient
right so when this happens um the king's
brother ganendra becomes the the Regent
the caretaker King because dendra is
still alive he's fighting for his life
in the hospital but after three four
days dendra also dies and ganendra
becomes the king of
Nepal and then I think it's around 20002
2001 that this happened the Royal
massacre in Nepal so very conveniently
the whole family is wiped out the
monarchy is wiped out the gandra is left
and uh the the terrorist Rebellion
against the government the monarchy
continues until the mid 2000s and
eventually the pressure I think became
so much that ganendra had to abdicate
his throne there was nothing cowardly or
something otherwise he would have been
next by the time it was all done you
know so and then you have the Communists
the maoists taking over and they still
they are still in power so we did this
we our government not we as in we the
people but our so-called government
destroyed the last Hindu monarchy of
Nepal that's what our government did
apparently allegedly raw was involved
allegedly okay you can look it
up so that's what the government of
India did and by doing so we we turned
Nepal into our civilizational Ally our
civiliz civilization brother into a
Chinese asset that's what that prime
minister
did what a genius that person must have
been H turning other civilizational
brother of civilizational Ally into a
Chinese
asset
that's what was
done disaster I mean that's what our
governments have been doing in the past
shooting our civilization in the foot
over and over and over
again and that's where we are
today okay cardboard Studio 684 says do
you enjoy reading sci-fi novels do I
now
uh um all sci-fi uh but yeah okay um do
I enjoy reading sci-fi novels do I have
a favorite do I have favorite authors
like Isaac Asimov
andir lein I'd love to hear your
thoughts on them additionally could you
recommend some lesser known sci-fi
novels particularly from Indian or
International authors that more people
should
read and yes thank you so much so uh
SciFi you know sci-fi is my favorite
genre of of literature as a kid all I
wanted to read was
sci-fi and as a kid I had access to a
University library and in that
University Library among the literature
section I discovered a whole bunch of
ancient books from the 1950s and 60s uh
they belong to something called the
science fiction book club based in
London but somehow this University had
acquired a bunch of these books and I
came across books that nobody has heard
of today uh sleeping Planet by William R
Burkett
Jr uh Invader on my back by Philip ehigh
the hephestus plague plague by Thomas
pige and so many more I I can't even
remember some of the names and all um a
book by Larry
nen what was it
called um I forget a gift from Earth a
gift from Earth by by Laren D some of
the Lesser known books so it's it's my
favorite genre there are so many I don't
have one favorite author I mean
obviously uh I admire the writings the
books the work of Aras clar for example
the the guy who spent his last few
decades in Sri Lanka uh one of his one
of the most impactful short stories that
he wrote was the Sentinel I think it was
written sometime in the 1940s before the
1950s The Sentinel incredible short
story then he came up he wrote Rondo
with Rama and the entire Rama series
which was extremely boring Rondo with
Rama was okay but then the remaining
three books were I did finish them I
have no idea how long it took me to
finish them I forced myself to finish
them and but they were awful awful but
2001 Space Odyssey and the entire series
that comes out of that that's wonderful
childhood's end was great from maasi
Clark um The Hammer Of God is an
interesting story the songs of distant
Earth then I liked the books written by
an astronomer and cosmologist called
Fred Hy so this guy is an actual was an
actual astronomer actual cosmologist but
he also wrote a couple of science
fiction books maybe more than a couple I
remember a for Andromeda wonderful book
and also something called the black
cloud that's another great book that he
wrote then you have writers like Robert
heinlin who wrote Starship Troopers
Stranger in a Strange Land the Moon is a
Harsh Mistress I mentioned Larry nen he
wrote Ring World he wrote co- wrote with
Jerry porell a mo the mo in God's eye of
course that book that I referred to the
a gift from
then classic science fiction by jul W
the French author wonderful books that
he wrote HG Wells he wrote The War of
the Worlds he wrote The Time Machine the
original science fiction author is Mary
Shelly who wrote
Frankenstein and so many other I can
mention William Gibson Neuromancer Cliff
seac Way Station interesting story which
I also read in the science fiction book
book club uh more modern writers like
Adrien chaikovsky the the children of
time the children of Ru all that that
story
um I stanislav LM the Polish writer who
wrote Solaris Philip K dick Do Androids
Dream of Electric Sheep Douglas Adams I
spoke about him yesterday the hitch
hitchikers guy to the Galaxy Asimov of
course I read Asimov I wrote I read uh
robots of dwn the caves of Steel all
that Asimov isn't that exciting from my
perspective but I did read many of his
books there's Philip K dick there's Kurt
fut there's chickin Leu the Chinese guy
who wrote uh three body problem Trilogy
there's the Nexus Trilogy somewhere here
behind me by rames Nam then there's Andy
veir the Martian project Hail Mary and
so on and so forth so many authors that
I could mention so many books I could
mention but I hope I've given some kind
of some kind of halfhazard guide so
science fiction and I could make a 2hour
video about that so yeah it's my
favorite genre I really enjoyed a
lot and a related question by
nkari what's your favorite science
fiction movie once again I don't have
one favorite science fiction movie there
are so many and within science fiction
movies there are sub genres there's
science fiction horror there is hard
science fiction there's fantasy science
fiction there is sci-fi comedy for
example one of my favorite movies is
Mars Attacks you should watch it a great
comedy science fiction comedy another
really wacky movie is The Fifth Element
Bruce Willis mil y Etc very funny movie
hard science
fiction the the book that I mentioned
from Arthur C Clark 2001 of Space
Odyssey that was turned into a movie by
Stanley cubrick that's a great movie
then alien I think it it may alien the
original alien from 1979 or something
that may well be perhaps the first scci
science fiction movie I watched as a
little kid and a little kid should never
watch a movie like that it was
frightening alien the original
alien with with what's her name the lady
who was in Avatar another the science
fiction movie um I forget her name I
forget names but she did a great job
she's the last survivor with the cat
right in in the movie
uh and then there's the the the followup
aliens so the first two or three movies
in the Alien series were fantastic
nowadays they're coming up with
ridiculous nonsense then the Star Wars
movies so Star Wars the the the first
Star Wars movie which came out in
whatever year 79 or whatever that's
another of the first science fiction
movies I watched I was a little kid and
I when I saw this thing on the big
screen I thought chewbecca was a gorilla
so Star War Star Trek it's not exactly a
movie it's a series on TV but that
contact by Carl Stan that I watched I
watched it in the early 2000s but I read
the book in the mid 1990s and it's so
funny that when I when you read a book
you imagine the characters and what's
happening right and I somehow the the
protagonist in contact is a lady I
forget the name of the character but I
imagine that character is Judy Foster
and eventually when the movie was made
that character was Judy Foster in the
movie that was
so yeah that was that was interesting
then Matrix Matrix one of the great
movies not the second and third one the
first one Matrix Terminator Terminator 2
Judgment Day wonderful movies Total
Recall Arnold scha Event Horizon Science
Fiction horror Blade Runner wonderful
atmospheric movie from the 1980s then
you have the Planet of the
Apes from the 1960s I believe Charlton
hon was there then the The Dawn of the
Planet of the Apes a more recent movie
with the the the man character is Caesar
right the the the ape then the Martian
that I mentioned in the book section and
of that's a great movie also Avatar I
mentioned very nice movie
Predator Predator from the 1980s Arnold
schwat again a movie by John Carpenter
the thing fantastic movie fantastic
movie science fiction horror once again
then Spielberg Close Encounters of the
third type Third Kind and there's a
movie science fiction horror Invasion of
the Body Snatchers Another Science
Fiction horror movie The
Fly then there's alien science fiction
Enemy Mine there's a movie by Will
featuring Will Smith Independence Day
there is a rather Fantastical Movie
called Armageddon with Bruce Willis in
which you're in space but you can still
walk as if you have
gravity there is that there was Edge of
Tomorrow
Edge of Tomorrow with uh Tom Cruz yes
there was uh I can remember other movies
like District 9 Jurassic Park is great
the abyss about aliens underwater under
the oceans there's a movie called X
makina about about uh artificial
intelligence and AI enabled
robots uh Interstellar great movie
wonderful
movie um and I could also give an honor
will mention the X Files which is not a
movie but it's it's a series I used to
watch as watch it as a kid as a teenager
M Muller and Scully that was good so
that's once again another halfhazard
random bunch of recommendations of
science fiction movies uh I'm sure I can
think of many more that also could be
another 1 hour video but I'll stop over
here okay Misha Monisha bwas asks a very
very profound question why does the
universe exist now before I even attempt
to answer it please understand this
question the subject matter of this
question we we're
dealing with the realm of philosophy
here okay not science this is bigger
than science this is
philosophy um so why does the universe
exist that's a fun question to think
about to
ponder
um imagine you are
a neuron a neuron cell look we got this
computer here super computer all of us
have
one how we use it it depends on us but
we have we all have one the brain the
human brain the most complicated machine
or object that we know of in the known
universe that's the human brain um now
and it's made of neurons trillions of
hundreds of billions of neurons maybe
trillions of neurons and the connections
and synapses and all that imagine you
are one of those neurons and and imagine
in this hypothetical reality that the
neurons can think and and and talk to
each other let's say the neurons are
thinking that we are all here sitting
here and we know there are so many of
us we inhabit such a vast Universe there
are hundreds of billions of us we can
all communicate with each
other what's the purpose of this
universe so as far as the neurons are
concerned the universe is what is
contained in the brain and they have no
idea of what's outside they don't even
know how how large the universe is
because it's hundreds of billions of
them right so as far as as they can see
there's neurons neurons neurons
everywhere and there are connections and
they can talk to each other pass signals
and that's how they live their life and
maybe one of them wonders what's the
purpose of this universe why does this
universe
exist so you
are just a neuron inside a brain your
purpose is you are part of the thinking
machinery and you're not aware of
it right now if you read science fiction
we were discussing science fiction
Douglas Adams the hitch hitchhikers guy
to the Galaxy in
that that book is existential philosophy
disguises science fiction comedy so in
that book the Earth was created as a
supercomputer and its purpose was to
find the answer to the ultimate
question the answer is
42 so the
Earth is an actual computer super
computer a mega super computer and all
the beings that inhabit the Earth they
are part of the program
programming and they're not aware of it
obviously right now what if the Earth is
too small to perform certain
calculations maybe even something larger
maybe a
Galaxy maybe the whole universe so maybe
the whole universe
perhaps could be a computer designed by
somebody to perform certain calculations
it will take a certain amount of time
maybe 20 Bill 20 billion years perhaps I
don't know how long it take and then
it'll output some answer and then its
purpose is done maybe the universe is a
Computing machine a calculating machine
it performs extraordinarily complicated
calculations that may be extraordinarily
complicated for us but for the beings
that designed this computer it may not
be that
complicated or maybe it is complicated
that's why they had to design a super
computer so look these are all
speculations do you understand these are
all speculations we don't know why the
universe exists but we know that
to to
perform very complicated calculations
you need larger and larger
computers with more and
more
components and some experiments need
computers that that are essentially as
large as the
universe or or for example if you want
to detect gravitational waves of a
certain
amplitude so right now we have
Lego and it allows us to uh detect
gravitational waves from black hole
collisions black hole neutral star
mergin and so on mergers and so on and
these collisions produce gravitational
waves with extremely large amplitudes
like a tsunami right tsunami is a huge
wave but we would like to detect
gravitational wave ripples tiny little
waves to have a detector of that
capability you would need the detector
would probably need to be the size of
the Milky Way or
something perhaps or maybe maybe the
size of the solar system I'm not sure we
can figure it out we can work it out on
on the back of a napkin that's the kind
of calculation it is but there you have
it so some experiments need very large
paresis and and some calculations need
extraordinar large computers so maybe
the universe itself is a computer and
it's it's performing some calculation
which will take a a certain amount of
time and we all are familiar with the
simulation hypothesis which once again
says that we are inside a simulation
this whole universe that we see is a
simulation inside a computer so maybe
that's what it is and it's a you know
it's a very plausible explanation about
the origin of the Universe yeah so that
could be the answer perhaps maybe there
are hyper intelligent beings hyper
intelligent Pand dimensional beings who
are running this simulation this the
universe is a super computer and we are
being we are in we are part of the
simulation maybe that's why it exists I
could give lots of different scenarios
that could perhaps possibly potentially
answer this question why does the
universe exist but without the requisite
amount of data
we can't satisfactorily answer the
question which is why the question and
the subject matter are within the realm
of philosophy not science but it it's
it's it's an
interesting thought process to have you
can go in multiple directions I spoke
about the civili hypothesis I spoke
about the universe possibly being a
super
computer there could be other scenarios
also that could potentially answer this
question but which is the right answer
we don't quite know but it's a question
one should Ponder from time to time and
actually try and work it
out using thought experiments that's
what we just did
here okay stepen 6050 says as we know
the
Universe um as the universe expands the
distance between galaxies increases okay
so by this does it mean that the
distance between the Sun and the Earth
the Earth of the other planets also
increases so this is an interesting uh
question so we have to understand that
we dealing with hubbles low over here
what is hubbles low let me try and put
that on um on on the screen give me a
second I'll have to type it type it over
here hubbles low so H hubbles constant
is H okay and it is approximately equal
to roughly 70
kilomet per second per Mega par SEC MPC
so let me add this banner and let me put
it over here on the screen okay so the
Hubble constant is roughly equal to
70 givot take kilometers per second per
Mega Parc okay now what is one Mega Parc
first of we know what a kilometer is we
know what a second is what's a mega Parc
so a mega Parc is approximately 3 * 10
ra to 6 light years three three million
Li years it's a unit of distance a very
large unit of
distance about 3 million Li years that's
one Mega par second so what does this
equation tell us this equation tells us
that a Galaxy which is one Mega par away
or 3 million Li years away will move
away from us at a speed of 70 km/
second it also tells us that if a galaxy
is 10 MEAP Parx away which is uh 30
million light years away then it will
move away from us at 700 kilometers per
second and if a galaxy is 100 MEAP Parx
away it'll move away from us at 7,000
kilom per second and so on so forth you
get it right so the further a galaxy is
away from us the faster it is it will be
moving away from us that's what it tells
us uh so let me uh remove that and we
come back to the question
okay now this applies at the largest
scales in the universe at of the order
of MEAP parex and more but when it comes
to very small distances like the solar
system and its radius it's tiny it's
minuscule compared to a mega Parc it
doesn't quite apply there so the
expansion of the universe it is it
becomes apparent and visible and and and
becomes relevant at very large distance
scales at short distance scales it is
the force gravity that
overpowers whatever is causing the
expansion of the universe so gravity is
a very weak Force but whatever is
causing the expansion of the universe
it's probably weaker than gravity at
Short distances short scales few light
years 10 20 light years 50 Li years
million Light Years
also
so because of that the distance between
the Sun in the earth and all that is not
changing it won't be affected by the
expansion of the universe and the the
the
the thing that's causing the expansion
of the universe it's called dark energy
which accounts for about 70% of the mass
energy of the
universe and this expansion of the
universe is not even going to affect the
gravitational relationship between the
Milky Way our home Galaxy and the
nearest large Galaxy Andromeda Andromeda
and Milky Way are coming towards each
other and in about 1.5 billion years
they will
merge not Collide but merge very messily
but eventually they'll merge into a very
large elliptical galaxy so the dark
energy the expansion of the universe the
Hubble law all that will not be able to
counteract that it only works at
extremely large distance scales all
right that's the
deal okay kithan lad 5451 says I've been
watching your podcast for a year now
thanks for doing okay thank you I
appreciate it sir um my first ever
question on YouTube I've read somewhere
that the quantum entanglement and spooky
action at a distance may be due to a
micro Wormhole that gets created between
the two particles if that is true then
would it be possible to create two
Quantum entangled devices or Gates that
would create a larger Wormhole that one
can travel through has there been any
scientific research on the subject okay
uh so this kind of research about
entangled vermes I think Juan malda has
written about this the idea was prop
proposed at at least a decade ago by
Leonard saskin one of the one of the
pioneers of string theory and so on
so what we talking about over here
entanglement and wormholes is from very
different kinds of physics when you're
talking about quantum entanglement we
talking about quantum mechanics spooky
action at the distance is what Einstein
supposedly called it and the Very crude
rough analogy is the pair of gloves
right I have a pair of gloves I pack
them to the two gloves separately I ship
one to Moscow I ship the other one to
Washington and when my friend in Moscow
opens one package and he finds let's say
a right-handed glove he knows that my
other friend in Washington she has got a
left-handed glove that sort of thing
right so the moment you see one you know
exactly what is the state of the other
one and let's say I've sent it not to a
person in Washington DC but I've sent it
to somebody in the Andromeda galaxy
which is 1.5 million Li years away or
whatever the distance is the moment the
person in Andromeda or the the being in
Andromeda opens the glove the package
and sees a left-handed glove it knows
immediately that the other one wherever
it is in Milky Way is a right handed
glove the two objects are
entangled knowing the state of one you
know immediately what the state of the
other is that's a very crude rough
analogy of quantum entanglement which is
when you produce a pair of particles
that are inherently entangled which
means that the two particles their state
can only be described by a single wave
function and then that's how
entanglement goes now that's quantum
mechanics which is the which is one of
the most successful theories in history
of physics extremely successful all of
our Technologies today most of them they
are based on quantum mechanics I mean we
would not be having this conversation
you know telecommunications all that
without Quantum Technologies
Technologies based quantum mechanics so
we know how to use quantum
mechanics and entanglement is one of the
strange phenomena at the he of quantum
mechanics now that's the the physics of
the ultra of the hyper microscopic World
subatomic World atoms molecules
subatomic particles uh and so on now
when we talk about worm holes we're
talking about general relativity which
is something which is an another
extremely successful branch of physics
theoretical physics but it operates at
the largest scales in the
cosmos in general relativity and quantum
mechanics are incompatible there are
fundamental thing problems within the
two that you cannot reconcile one with
the
other so now and
yet when you look at the let's say the
simplest black hole solution you know
Einstein came up with general relativity
1915 1916 and he has the Einstein field
equations and when you solve the
simplest
problem in when it comes to the Einstein
field equations which is a uncharged
non-rotating spherical black
hole which is the schz Ste solution you
get a solution with two black holes
connected by a wormhole essentially
which seems to be a curiosity but we
have two black holes connected by a
vermo now if you were to do a thought
experiment where you entangle two black
holes because a black hole is kind of
like
a like like like
um it's almost like a one of the
fundamental particles right a black hole
in a way if you were to entangle two
black holes and you work out the physics
in math it's like you they describe a
geometry which is a
wormhole that sort of thing so yeah
there could be some kind of connection
between entangled man entanglement and
in
wormholes whether it's a micro Wormhole
probably not a microor proper Einstein
Rosen
Bridge um so that's the kind of thing
that that we have it's a very
interesting uh Avenue in theoretical
physics not sure if it can resolve the
fundamental problems when it comes to
trying to combine general relativity in
quantum mechanics but very interesting
very interesting uh
Avenue of research so this is all
theoretical right now we don't know how
to create two Quantum entangled devices
we know how to create create entangled
photons or entangled set of sets of
particles and all that we kind of know
how to do that uh but how to create an
entangled set of worm black holes we
don't we we don't even know if black
holes really exist okay we see uh
objects that seem to fulfill all the
criteria of being a black hole Signa 61
is the first one we discovered and much
more so black holes most likely exist
okay but we have no access to a black
hole we don't want to have access to a
black hole in a lab because it'll eat
everything POS possibly so how do you
create entangled black holes and so on
and once again wormholes are hypothetic
are theoretical
objects no one's ever observed a
wormhole it's possible that quazars or
what appears to be black holes may
actually be worm holes it's it's very
possible but we have no idea of knowing
if it's thr on so verm holes again are
theoretical objects we don't know if
they exist if they exist there are all
kinds of problems that would want them
to to the Wormhole to snap
shut uh so unless you play some kind of
exotic material like like negative mass
or something inside a wormhole or or a
cosmic string inside a wormhole it won't
stay open and even then will it be
traversible or not we don't know so when
we're talking about traversable worm
holes we're talking about engineering
actually and when it comes to these
these matters we are nowhere near
starting any engineering projects on
them okay it's all theoretical right now
so wonderful question very interesting
topic but we are in the infancy of
research in this
matter okay yaj noala says what are the
negative effects of microplastics found
in breast milk and testicles also sperm
count is deining among men over the past
few decades do you think it's worrying
it's very worrying very
problematic it's one of the factors
that's contributing to declining birth
rates U low sperm count low sperm
quality poor sperm quality decreasing
testosterone all problematic very
problematic on a on a on a Countrywide
Nationwide scale on a culture-wide scale
on on on a global scale extremely
problematic
because low birth rates you may say that
India needs low birth rates we have 1.4
billion people
Etc I understand I agree we have too
many people we need to have ideally a
population of 300 million which is
almost 1/4 one fif of what we are so
what do you do do we have everybody have
just one child then we will end up with
a disaster like China what happens with
declining birth rates is that the
population starts aging the median age
starts increasing rapidly imagine I mean
look at Japan what's happened to Japan
their total fertility rate is 1.1 1
Point Whatever It Is by 2050 the average
age of the average per the age of the
average person in Japan will be around
60 or maybe more imagine a nation where
everybody is 60 plus the average person
is 60 plus where's going to where will
you have the energy the Vitality that
you need for a nation to progress it's
going to be a disaster very few children
very soon the the nation will be in
shambles the same thing is happening to
China so if you want to decrease your
population from let's say 1.4 billion to
300 million you have to plan this
decline in population over two centuries
otherwise you're not thinking
right
so this low sperm count low sperm
quality low testosterone levels is is
is very very concerning and and very
dangerous especially for a nation like
India I mean for every nation of course
but we we are looking at from looking at
this from our perspective right so we
have to ensure that India's total
fertility rate stays around 2.1 right
now it's already 2.0 in some states it's
1.7 1.6 so it's it's warning signs right
now for
India and there a lot of factors
contribute to this I'll not go into that
now I'll let's talk about the
microplastics uh look microplastics are
when plastic
plastic whatever you know plastic is
used every everywhere
right cups and
disposable containers and and plastic
bags for for grocery shopping all kinds
of stuff it's eventually dumped in the
garbage and it ends up in the oceans and
then it degrades over time degrades and
then it breaks up but it doesn't the the
molecules remain right so it um
eventually over time it becomes very
small very small particles emerge like a
millimeter half a mill in size maybe
maybe less than whatever roughly that's
that that that sort of dimensions and
that's called microplastics and
microplastics are everywhere now
apparently and they're discovering
microplastics in people's brains in in
testicular tissue in in breast tissue
Etc now this will cause all kinds of
problems hormonal problems blockages
whatnot
Plastics see plastic is manufactured
through a certain process of
distillation when you have crude oil you
put that in a very large tubular
container kind of thing very tall thing
and you heat it to a certain temperature
and then you distill it so the highest
the the lightest one is something and
then you have the bottom you have ban
which is tar and you have diesel
somewhere in the middle and so on so
that's how you can separate the
different kinds the different kinds of
uh um hydrocarbon materials that come
out of it some of it becomes aviation
fuel or kerosene and some of it is the
lightest one I think is gasoline or
petrol and somewhere in between you have
what becomes eventually is converted
into plastic so there's all kinds of
chemic chemicals in this phyto phyto
whatever or something I don't remember
what the term is various kind of
chemicals that can affect your endocrine
system your
hormones that can create hormonal
problems some of the uh chemicals in
these Plastics could create uh
irritation in the body which could lead
to inflammation of a permanent state of
inflammation which can lead to cancer or
other other problems then if you have
microplastics in in breast tissue then
they could lead to blockages in in the
in the milk ducts or whatever or it
could have the leeching of these
chemicals into the um into the body of
the infant who's going to drink milk so
on when you have this in testical you
may have testicular cancer you may have
testicular blockages or or inflammation
and cancer whatnot so it's overall a
disaster situation it's not good at all
and the solution is to stop the use of
plastics but plastic is so convenient
right plastic we need it for everything
from packaging to to to home delivery of
whatever stuff and just about everything
it's something I suppose we're going to
have to live with somehow the Romans
lived with lead in their water now we
are dealing with plastic in our water
supply and whatnot so there we are
okay geopolitical du says why is creit
so unpopular in East and Southeast Asia
it's England's national sport then why
does England not promote it in Europe
and America England is is as a hasb
nation it's no longer a powerful entity
it's second or third rate geopolitical
power unfortunately right since 1956 or
whatever 56 57 58 so uh they don't have
much of hard power left and when you
don't have much hard power your soft
power becomes negligible and and and it
is of no use so so England doesn't do
much to promote its culture it's its its
national sport uh in Europe in America I
think Romania plays some form of cricket
in the US you have Indian and
subcontinental origin people who play
cricket and they have recently the US
team defeated Pakistan that was funny
and so on but overall it's it's not very
popular in Southeast Asia East Asia
because these regions were never
colonized by England but let me tell you
me let me show you interesting something
really interesting shall we uh let's go
to Google Search which we haven't opened
today okay we have Google search open
here and let's search for
kilikiti what is kilikiti one wonders
let's let's let's open this
kilikiti so one second so
kilikiti let's open this it is San
Cricket or k I it's one of several forms
of the gra of cricket it originates in
Sawa English
missionaries introduced this gra in the
early 19th century and it spread
throughout Polynesia and this is what
the bats look like they don't look like
your standard cricket bats they look
like some kind of weapon or something
similar to somewhat similar to a
baseball bat and it's
played in Polynesia and among Polynesian
populations that's what a bat looks like
Jo Liv Australian cricketer he
photographed doing this what are the
rules let's let's see if there are
rules the rules of the rules of kilikiti
are flexible indeed the majority of
reports written on the game simply say
that the rules can only be known by
those
playing so there's a batting team A
Feeling team a pitch sometimes of
concrete the ball alternates between the
two Bowlers one at each end of the peach
and there are two Wicket Keepers there
is no limit to team size
and teams are made up of whoever turns
up regardless of gender and age tourist
accounts mention that strangers are
often welcomed and most players are
typically
all-rounders a kiliki game is a
multi-day community event full of
singing dancing and feasting and so on
and the one universal rule is that the
host team forfeits if it cannot provide
enough
food uh if you want to look at images of
the sport let's see images so you have
as you can see a couple of ladies
playing Kilik kti um and a game in
progress and you can see the native
dress that they wear you know left left
arm fast
bowler various players and so on so this
is the game of kilikiti I had come
across this I don't know how many years
ago but I
thought that this was something
really
funny so yeah just just sharing this
knowledge this
information okay next
question okay next question is by Imran
Nai the question is why do Pash people
not want to say that Pashto language is
40%
Sanskrit uh the other 60% is Arabic
porian words uh but the remaining is
sanskrit the following P this is very
interesting the following PTO words
might be of Sanskrit or Indian origin in
my opinion liil
writing dubal drowning yeah dubna right
in Hindi darim I fear
Dar uh sukal Cal ganel counting Gan is
is math the arithmetic right in in
Sanskrit Su um jba Tong jba right in
Sanskrit Musa smile it's like musan in
in
poran de a lot lug Pew Manel accepting
patang butterfly in s it's chra patanga
right or
Pang uh Lial writer Roy bread Roy is Roy
everywhere pan
Leaf uh angut Pinger that comes from
Sanskrit once again PADI pares
stranger well parades is sunkit Once
Again Sam samudra river sest srishti is
nature gurel seeing lari L is wood we
understand that of course satel is
keeping duck is
fool Sima his
face mgar in Hindi milala friend okay KH
is Village dager is field Bahar is out
andik is
distress B is shape bindii bindii is
okra okay is a dress lay is fighting in
brto P is feeding okay okay okay that's
okay I can see that G1 is life good god
really uh bul is saying band is blocked
chhatri is umbrella comes from the word
chhatra in Sanskrit Dan is seed it's
incredible how many of the of the words
in PTO have
clear Sanskrit origin and we can see the
similarities between these words and
let's say languages like Hindi as well
so it's it's really interesting and the
question
is um the question you're asking is why
do pashun people not want to say that
PTO language is 40% Sanskrit and the
other 60% is loone words from Arabic and
Persian but 60% Sanskrit
look it's it's very clear that there's a
tremendous amount of Sanskrit
uh origin to many of the words in
Pashto uh why do people who speak Pashto
why do pashon people not want to admit
this that the origin is sanskrit it's
because of what they've been taught for
the past 10,000 years that we are the
descendants of some kind of um Jewish
tribe one of the Lost tribes of Israel
so most most pashon people will they
believe they genuinely believe it's not
their fault they believe it they believe
that they are of Jewish origin that's
what they've been told uh why they've
been told told this I
look gandar was the first part of of bat
to fall to the Turks and then it went to
hell essentially and now this is the
society that's emerged um so the true
native of
Afghanistan who have been who have been
the natives for thousands of years other
pashon people and their origin is
definitely subcontinental not
turkic but they have been conditioned
brainwashed or whatever into believing
that they are not Turks but uh Jews of
Jewish
origin and because of this conditioning
mental conditioning and this belief they
will not agree that PTO is of Indian or
or subcontinental origin and the root
vocabulary is is uh Sanskrit vocabulary
they they won't admit it unfortunately
don't blame them for it but that's what
it is unfortunate but I'm I'm so
grateful to you for bringing out this
entire list of of of of common
words
um and uh I really appreciate that very
much so thank
you okay balam Putin says what's the
difference between a freedom fighter and
nationalist when I search on Ms Edge for
Mr Gandhi it says Indian freedom fighter
and it shows people like Nashandra BOS V
sarar bhagat Singh Bal gangadhar tilak
Chandra shikar Azad as nationalists who
act and these are the people who
actually in genuinely led us in the
freedom struggle so what's the
difference between a freedom fighter in
the Indian context and a nationalist in
the Indian context or Global
context nationalism is seen as evil
today in the
west because I've I've given this
example
before go let's go back at let's go back
to Millennia to the Roman Empire when
the Roman Empire controlled much of
Europe North Africa all that do you
think it would have been happy with the
rise of nationalism in let's say Judea
in in in in th in in carage in Germania
Germania do you in Gaul which is France
do you think the Romans would have been
happy with the rise of nationalism in
various places
no nationalism would have been a bad
word during the Roman Empire everyone is
a Roman citizen be happy with that don't
ever try to be nationalistic nationalism
is evil so that's the Roman Empire today
you have the US Empire they control
Europe EU is one nation essentially and
nationalism French nationalism German
nationalism evil evil no no no we are
all members of the EU so that everybody
can be rolled so nationalism is evil and
nationalist is a bad word in the west
okay um they want it's it's become very
Marxist they want the collective to be
prioritized over the individ the the the
the nation and the individual to be
prioritized over the family that sort of
craziness so n nationalism is
nationalism is bad in today's Western
context so they portray people like Nagi
subash Chandra BOS who took up arms
against the British as a nationalist
because nationalism is evil they portray
v
sarer as evil they portray bhat Singh is
evil and so on because these people they
wanted to put up an actual fight against
the Britain an 1857 kind of fight as
opposed to a fake fight where you do
nothing passive resistance that's not
resistance at all so um that's why they
portray these these people as
nationalists because nationalist is a
bad word it has negative connotations in
the
west and and you will see certain Indian
textbooks that outright say that people
like bhat Singh chra Sharad are
terrorists
okay so that's all about mentally
brainwashing the Indian population and
it's very successful and Mr Gandhi of
course was an Indian Freedom Fighter so
as long as you are passive and
nonviolent and you actually do nothing
you are a freedom fighter because you
despite you not fighting at all but if
you actually put up a fight you're a
nationalist really bad so that's the
kind of brainwashing that you find in
Indian textbooks and
across the internet
globally to put forth a certain
narrative to keep
Indians keep to keep on be to keep on to
to perpetuate the sheeplike mentality of
Indians
ainsa don't fight don't put up
resistance be passive be nonviolent
accept your
fate be sheep that's what right don't be
leaders be sheep so that's why this
entire narrative exists and most Indians
have swalled this Hook Line and Sinker
very
sadly yulka says would it be correct to
say that Hindu Hindu ethics and morality
is exceptionally good compared to ethics
of all other non-pagan and Pagan
monotheistic and polytheistic societies
Greco Roman ethics Han Chinese ethics
Aboriginal Australian ethics Native
American ethics Etc if yes what explains
this
exceptionalism also what explains the
seemingly widespread nature of sexual
slavery in many Civilizations for
example GRE Roman Han Chinese
civilization Etc except the Hindu
civilization this seems to paint a bleak
picture of mankind doesn't it well this
is a very controversial
topic but I agree with
[Laughter]
you yes we have historically had the
most Superior
ethics
okay let's substantiate this claim with
some
facts slavery human sex sacrifice let's
take these two things did India bhat bat
ARA Etc ever had slavery ever have
slavery is slavery something that's
accepted in our civilization in our
culture no absolutely not we've never
had slavery the only times we had
slavery when we were under foreign
occupation are the Turks or uh the the
Europeans the
Christians that's when we hit slavery
when India was free and self-governed by
by Indian kings queens whatever Emperors
we never had slavery ever ever did
Greece ancient Greece have slavery of
course it had slavery it's well known
look at that did Rome have slavery of
course there was slavery in Rome it was
rampant Alexander the
Greek which city did he destroy thbes
was
it uh so he he besieges this the city of
Thieves and after a certain period of
time The Siege succeeds and the walls
are broken and then he's so upset that
the siege lasted so long and he you know
that thing is there that
he uh has a significant amount of the
number of the population executed and
the rest is slow sold into
slavery slavery was part of Greek
culture the Greek culture helenic
culture is very similar in a lot of ways
to Indian culture to the older Vic
culture but we never had slavery they
had slavery the Romans had slavery
rampant
slavery that's two examples in the Indo
European world the Germans had slavery
the the the the the the the Vikings had
slavery the ghouls had slavery the Kelts
had slavery everybody had slavy we did
not have it the Chinese had slavery of
course Human Sacrifice the Greeks had
human sacrifice the Romans had Human
Sacrifice the Kelts had Human
Sacrifice um let's not even talk about
arage let's not even go there uh the
Germanic tribes had Human Sacrifice the
Vikings had Human
Sacrifice the breons breons had human
sacri everybody had it India you cannot
imagine the horror of human
sacrifice most strong taboo you can ever
imagine
Chinese well not sure if you had Human
Sacrifice but executions on the scale of
hundreds of thousands and millions were
was quite common so once again we have
very different ethics and when it comes
to things like horrific things like
sexual slavery we can't even imagine
that in our culture right but it was
there in other cultures so we overall it
is a fact look I have now whatever
claims I've made here whatever I've said
why don't you if you if you're not sure
if it's it's true or not don't ask me
for
sources use Google and find your
sources okay little bit of work you have
to do right if you want to learn
something so please don't ask me for
sources for what I just said look it up
all the information is available in
public not behind any firewall any pay
wall everything is available in the
public domain you just have to do a
little bit of work and type in some
Search terms in Google or your favorite
search so please do
that so it's clear that we had Superior
ethics and
morality but we we had insufficient
levels of of ruthlessness and barbarity
at certain times during the Ashokan
morian times we had sufficient
ruthlessness not barbarity but
ruthlessness oh absolutely ashoke was
the man wasn't he
during times of rulers like kishka the
great uh samudra Gupta the
great so cholas rajendra Chola the great
we were we were not Divo of ruthlessness
at all but there were times when certain
things went wrong overall so yes we had
the most Superior ethics no question
about it today the West claims
superiority based on certain other
factors U but we know what the truth is
right so it does indeed paint a b Bleak
P Bleak picture of of humankind mankind
it does unfortunately it
does and Y again says should Hindu
religion become aggressively engaged in
proactive conversion both in India and
in the entire world at least with
respect to people who are themselves
followers of religions which are engaged
in proactive conversion look why is it
that we are not supposed to prati we are
not supposed to engage in conversion
activities we're supposed to just keep
on absorbing this
nonsense the two big religions in the
world Christianity Islam
they aggressively prati right they seek
to convert more and more people into the
flock why shouldn't Hinduism do that why
not we should I think we should do that
and to me I don't care about a person's
skin color or or
ethnicity but the culture the religion
is something that would uh matter more
in my opinion for example Kamala Harris
is half Indian does she feel Indian to
you at all Tuli gabard has 0% in Indian
ethnicity but she's way more Indian
someone like Kamala Harris or bab
Jindal or or or or what's her name Nikki
Haley these Bobby Jindal Nikki Haley are
100% pure Indian right ethnicity wise
but are they Indian culturally at all do
they feel Indian to you they don't to
see Gard feels Indian despite not having
Indian ethnicity so culture matters DNA
doesn't
matter so I think we need to bring more
people into our cultural umbrella I
think we should do that but it takes a
lot of funding to do this we have people
who are very wealthy we have a
tremendous amount of funding overall
available to us but we don't use it in
that direction that's the unfortunate
thing so I think the Hindu religion
should get become aggressively engaged
in proactive conversion activities why
not we're doing something good we saw we
have Superior ethics right so we should
bring in more people into into our camp
essentially into our dharmic umbrella
into the dharmic fold we should do that
I agree but you need funding for that
and you need some leadership for that
you need leadership leadership is the
most important thing in all of this do
we have the right kind of leaders do we
have the right kind of leaders or do we
have fake vabi leaders who pretend to be
leaders and who have no leadership
quality introspect about
that ramal Lakshmi says men and women
sports uh so men and women compete
separately in sports because of their
physical aspects in most games football
wrestling weightlifting Etc but I'm
curious why is there segreg ation in
games such as chess or shooting Etc
which requires more thinking and focus
and that's a very U pertinent relevant
question for example in the case of a
sport like
chess what's the deal let's let's take a
look at the rankings in chess shall we
so let
let's go to ratings. F fid.com shall
we ratings do fid.com
and here you have
ratings the top 100 players I think this
is the
open ratings so magnos Carlson Hikaru
Etc let me just go back we have the
open ratings Magnus cars is number one
with a rating of
2832 who's number 100
100 is a guy called mmed of R from aeran
2637 2637 who's the top rated women
woman she is 2633 below the top 100 men
so for for some reason the top rated
woman has a rating that's below the
100th rated man in
chess okay and then we can look at the
the the women's ratings if you want and
all that but I'm not going to do that so
the top rated woman is below the 100th
rated man for some reason so there seems
to be something in
chess that for some
reason men perform better than women the
top 100
men uh are higher are better at chest
than the top top ranked woman for some
reason should not be that way but it is
that way for some
reason so I think think the former woman
world number one yudit pogar had said
that we need to do away with the
segregation and have everybody compete
at the same level maybe something will
change I don't know uh I don't think
there should be a physical
Factor when it comes to a game like
chess men women should be able to
compete on the same level but for some
reason there exists this
disparity so maybe we should file some
something like this you know a few years
have everybody compete irrespective of
gender on the same level and let's see
how it
goes uh that could be tried once again
when it comes to shooting whe whether it
is you know uh ski shooting rifle or
pistol or whatever or or archery archery
you would need some strength I think the
male shoulder is way stronger than the
female trer but when it comes to things
like shooting you know when it comes to
rifles or or pistols or whatever I don't
think it makes any difference whether
you're a male or a female I'm sure that
females can outperform males at least in
in those ports so I think there should
not be segregation in sports like
shooting why is there segregation
probably from for historical reasons so
even in games or Sports where physical
strength is not really a factor I think
historically men used to compete more
let's go back 100 years 1900 I think
women were marginalized invest in
society at the time right so even in a
sport like shooting or whatever it would
be male who would males would compete 90
males versus like 10 women and that's
why it made sense for women who did not
get so many opportunities to be allowed
to compete in a separate category and I
think that's the tradition that's
continued until
now uh so so gender segregation and
sports makes sense in boxing mixed
martial arts in wrestling in in a
variety of sports um track and field all
that but probably not so much in in
chess or or or shooting ET
so maybe one should do away with those
uh with the segregation in chess and
shooting and see how it goes probably
women may do much better than what most
people would expect in
this okay the feminist Slayer says my
mother has a serious medical condition
in the report the doctor concluded she
won't be in this world for long I'm very
sorry to hear that sir so mother doctor
has indicated had indicated this four
years ago excuse me thinking about this
my whole graduation years went into
depression my relatives are trying to
subjugate me I don't have any job I just
have an observed degree of BC and don't
have the necessary life skills currently
to get a job in the market I was just
good at academics should I try for a
government job to escape from the
situation as early as possible and then
plan plan my life further I'm from a
lower middle class family also my mother
burned my college degree I have never
felt this type of Agony in my life
before How could a mother do this to a
son so yeah that's that's terrible to
hear I'm very sorry as to what you have
gone through um yeah how could a mother
do this to her son mothers should not do
that to to their sons but you know not
everybody is fortunate enough to have
good parents unfortunately uh there are
historical examples of of bad
parenting uh Queen Victoria was a
notoriously bad mother you know the the
the Empress of India the biggest drug
Smuggler in history he was a notoriously
bad mother she was extremely cruel to
her son Edward I believe her name was
his name was who became the next king
she was really cruel to him so that's an
example of historical bad mother uh the
mother of George Washington the founding
the first president of the US she was
very cruel to her son she publicly
humiliated him so many times and uh she
supported his enemies she supported the
British over her son and so on so she
was another very cruel mother so there
there have been examples of this you
know it's something that doesn't happen
often but look it is what it is it's
it's the Cs the gods have dealt you
dealt dealt you with and you just accept
it and move on so uh so first thing is
there's no point wallowing in self-pity
don't feel sorry for
yourself understand the situation coolly
dispassionately and find a solution so
now the first thing you have to do is
find a job your your main draw the main
problem in your life right now is that
you don't have a job and you don't have
an income which makes you vulnerable to
all kinds of things the first thing you
have to do is get a job and get an
income that way you become independent
of others you don't have to depend on
anybody else so get a job first thing
whatever jobs available you can get a
government job you can get some other
job temporarily whatever it takes get
yourself an income and become
independent that way nobody can
subjugate you and nobody can do a thing
to you you become independent once you
become financially independent then it
may take you some time
to to position yourself in your life
into where you really want it to be that
may take time but that's life
look everybody some people get all the
luck maybe it's unfair and some people
who are good are unlucky and that's also
unfair but look you can't blame
luck you have to do the best with
whatever you've got in
life um so I would say be strong
mentally first thing is to get yourself
a job and get yourself an income so that
nobody can subjugate you or do whatever
they want to do and then once you have
that then you can plan your next moves
and it may take you some time to get
very to to get where you want to be in
life five years 10 years going to take
so what that's
life okay so go for it be strong be
mentally strong and uh at the end of the
day don't allow anybody to to subjugate
you and take advantage of you become
independent and uh do the best that you
can in life I'm sure you'll do do well
provided you're mentally strong and you
keep your emotions out of the picture
and think coldly dispassionately
strategically and think
longterm all the best sir all the best I
really wish you the
best par says please tell me how to
study and from where I'm having my je
Mains in January first attempt in April
second attempt in IIT paper in June or
July how to complete syllabus in six or
seven months since you are also from
Science Background kindly tell is it
possible and how and how to kill
distractions please help resources also
look I am not very familiar with itg Etc
but what I can tell you is I can give
you an overall set of principles on and
on how to deal with this 67 months
definitely possible provided you have a
reasonable background in the
subject
uh look je is about clearing an exam
right it doesn't it's not about really
acquiring the entire width and breadth
and depth of knowledge that you
otherwise would need to have all you
need to learn is how to crack the exam
so I would say that you
can um you need to acquire the past few
years question papers if such a thing is
available for J or you can enroll in
some some something like an academy if
they I'm sure they have something with J
right I'm sure it'll cost money but
that's one thing you can do the main
thing is you have to solve lots and lots
of problems solve lots and lots of exam
papers and just learn how to clear the
exam that's it don't try to acquire the
deepest and broadest knowledge in the
thing it's about being very
strategic and just learning how to clear
the exam that's all it is that's what
all all the G is so that's what you can
do 6 seven months if you have that much
time it's definitely enough to do that
provided you have a reasonable
background in the subject um how to kill
distractions you to change your
environment to kill
distractions it's like uh you know when
when someone wants to lose weight their
nutritionist dietitian whatever doctor
will come to their house they will open
their fridge open all the drawers and
remove all the junk food and throw it in
the in the in the dust bin in the waste
bin right and replace all of that with
with healthy food the same thing you
would do with your distractions if you
have distractions on on your phone
delete all those apps if you have still
a distraction with your phone get
yourself a dumb phone not a smartphone
if you have people who are distracting
you try and distance yourself from those
people if you whatever it is you have to
remove those distractions physically
from the environment that you are in and
then you can focus so that's what you
need to do that's what I can say in
brief all the best sir all the
best okay I will take a couple of
questions from the live
chat a very small number of questions
from the live chat because we've already
gone past two hours 10 minutes uh it is
very difficult to explain Go's
incompleteness theorem in just two or
three minutes maybe next time I'll do
that but I do U appreciate the
question
uh okay
um Bobby e says did you hear about the
several thousand years old Tamil Bell
found in New Zealand yes I've heard
about it I'm I'm not sure if it's
several thousand years old but it's
definitely definitely an ancient Bell
that they have found in New Zealand how
did it get there we're not quite sure
maybe see we were Travelers right we
were India was India is the oldest known
Maritime civilization and Indians were
seaf firers going who traveled far and
wide Indians have been living on the
east coast of Africa for centuries
thousands of years probably and if you
could go all the way to East Africa you
could all go all the way to New Zealand
and Australia as well and we know that
Indians reached Australia about 5,000
years before today because we can see
the genetic imprint of Indians of of of
subcontinental DNA among the Aboriginal
DNA aborigin population today roughly
10% of the Aboriginal DNA is of Indian
origin so if Indians reached Australia
New Zealand isn't too far away so
somehow we reach there and the bell has
Tamil inscriptions which would say that
it's not like 5,000 years old maybe
sometime somewhere in the past 2,000
years so I've heard of it vaguely I
don't remember the details but really
interesting uh Discovery and kind of
adds one more layer to the picture
right okay let's take maybe one more
question yes India won second gold in
the chess Olympiad so was it the the
girls the women who won not
sure I can see some really funny all
right I won't take them up but yeah I'm
really glad India won this second gold
in the chess Olympia India is going to
be a superpower in
chess uh an Mel says I'm not able to
have beard even at the age of 23 what to
do forget it how does it
matter look some people it doesn't
matter I know that when you have some
when you want something and you when
something isn't available then you you
really want it right there are people
who have wonderful curly hair and you
will see them going and buying hair
straighteners why and then you have
people who have straight hair who will
buy hair curlers why you have people who
have thick beards who want a less thick
beard there are people who can't really
grow too much of a beard who want a full
beard so whatever it is that we don't
have we desire that my point is move on
in life what matters is what you do with
your life how successful you are how
much of an impact you have on society
how much money you earn and how much all
of that you know that is what matters in
life if you can't grow a beard it's a
genetic thing or whatever it is it
doesn't matter you go to Mongolia you go
to China you go to Japan you go to Korea
most people can't grow a full beard do
they have a big complex about that they
don't it doesn't matter in
life okay I don't think Elon Musk is
capable of growing a full beard he's got
well you know it doesn't matter is my
point all right don't think too much
about
it go out there and succeed in life all
right and with this I think I will I
already spoke about the tirupati Prasad
issue it is
unacceptable all right and something
needs to do about this the people who
are responsible for this need to be
brought to
Justice okay with this I'm going to end
today's session thank you so much for
all the questions you asked as always
very interesting questions and let's uh
next weekend I I will not have a have a
I won't have the live streams because
I'm traveling but I'm going to release a
bunch of podcasts the the next 10 days
or so a whole backlog of podcast that
I'm not released I'm going to release
those with a with a interval of two
three days two three days okay so that's
what you can look forward to the next
week or two and the next weekend I'm
going to be back on the live streams so
until then thank you so much once again
for the questions and keep asking
questions keep raising your standards
and I'll see you reasonably very soon
okay until then take care bye-bye